ILGWU. Local 10. Managers' correspondence 5780/012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Local 10. Managers' correspondence
1938-1948
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Nagler, Isidore, 1895-
Falikman, Moe
Local 10
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/012
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Correspondence.
The collection contains the correspondence of Isidore Nagler, Manager of the Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, Local 10 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5457245
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 31, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, May 19, 2014
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Biographical / Historical
Isidore Nagler (1895-1959) came to the United States from Austria-Hungary in 1909 and joined Local 10 of the ILGWU in 1911. He held various positions within the ILGWU, including business agent of Local 10, manager of the New York Cloak Joint Board, international vice president, and manager of the New York Joint Board of the Cloak, Shirt, Skirt and Reefer Makers' Union. He was also involved in the work of the New York State Federation of Labor, American Federation of Labor, American Labor Party, Liberal Party, and the Jewish Labor Committee.
Biographical / Historical
The Cutters of Local 10 can be traced back to the Gotham Knife Cutters of 1884 and the United Cloak Cutters in 1886 by the Knights of Labor. These were the predecessors of Local 15 and 6 which were chartered by the ILGWU in 1902 and merged to become Local 10 in 1906. Local 10 played a lead role in the 1910 cloakmakers' strike. Local 10 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), was also known as the Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, and based in New York City. Isidore Nagler was Manager of the Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, Local 10 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union from 1939 to 1952.
Scope and Contents
The collection is composed of correspondence of Local 10 managers Isidore Nagler. Amalgamated Cutters' Union Local 10 was a member of the Joint Board of Cloak, Suit, Skirt and Reefer Makers' Union, as well as the Joint Board of the Dress and Waistmakers' Union. Local 10 held a unique position in that its members were split between both Joint Boards. Cutters of cloaks belonged to the Cloak Joint Board and cutters of dresses belonged to the Dress Joint Board. Local 10's dual position in the Joint Boards is reflected in the records.
There are administrative records of managing the local, including records, documents and correspondence from the International. Various departments are represented (Auditing, Education, Research), as well as other locals. There is the correspondence of Max Goldenberg, who was the secretary of Local 10.
Manufacturers' associations found in the collection include the Affiliated Dress Manufacturers, Inc., Associated Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers, Infants and Childrens' Coat Association, Merchants Ladies Garment Association, National Dress Manufacturers Association, and Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers, Inc.
Available is material documenting local elections, including nominations and signed resignation cards. Of particular importance is the information regarding the ILGWU practice (according to Article 5 Section 28 of the ILGWU constitution) that required newly elected and installed officers to sign undated resignation forms to be deposited with the union. Similar material is also found in 5780/011. And there is also cases that were brought before the executive board, and the decisions of the Impartial Chairman.
Similar and complementary records can be found in 5780/011 Local 10 Managers' Correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/001: ILGWU. Local 10 minutes 5780/001 mf: ILGWU. Local 10. Microfilm 5780/008: ILGWU. Local 10 dues books 5780/011: ILGWU. Local 10. Managers' correspondence 5780/094: ILGWU. Local 10 membership record books 5780/131: ILGWU. Local 10 records
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Women's clothing industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- New York (State) -- New York; Industrial relations -- United States; Industrial relations -- New York (State) -- New York; Nagler, Isidore,1895-; Nagler, Isidore, 1895-; Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union.
5457245
- A, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Incl. statement by Dean Alfange before House of Representatives on the rescue of the Jewish people of Europe; address by Dean Alfange, November 1943.
- Ames, Arnold. Case, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Agreements (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Corres. on negotiations w. independent firms, agreements.
- American Labor Party, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Associations., 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Affiliated Dress Manufacturers, Inc..
- Associations., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Allied Underwear Association.
- Associations. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Incl. American Cloak & Suit Mfrs. Assoc.; Assoc. Corset & Brassiere Mfrs., Inc.; Industrial Assoc. of Juvenile Apparel Mfrs., Inc.
- Associations., 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Incl. Infant's & Children's Coat Assoc., Inc. 1943-47; letters from Executive Director Charles Baker Informing Local on cutters employed by members of the Assoc.
- Associations., 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Incl. Merchant Ladles Garment Assoc. 1943-47; National Assoc. of Blouse Mfrs., 1944-45.
- Associations., 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Incl. National Dress Mfrs. Assoc., 1943-47; National Skirt & Sportswear Assoc.; Negligee Mfrs., 1943-45; Popular Priced Dress Mfrs., 1943-45; United Better Dress Mfrs. & United Popular Dress Mfrs. Assoc.
- B, 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- C, 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Central High School of Needle Trades, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Incl. Corres. w. Mortimer C. Ritter.
- Central Trades and Labor Council., 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Cloak Joint Board, N.Y., 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Incl. Corres. w. Israel Feinberg on Union related matters & drive conducted by United Jewish Appeal; P. Herman manager Organization & Patrol Dept. on investigation of firms.
- Cloak Joint Board, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Cloak Joint Board, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Isidor Stenzor & Israel Feinberg reports.
- Cloak Joint Board, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Incl. proposals to Associations for negotiations in the cloak & suit industry.
- Cloak Joint Board, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Hearings before Impartial chairman Charles Poletti on increase in wages, October 1946.
- Cloak Joint Board. Retirement Fund, Coat and Suit Industry, 1944-1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Corres. w. Herbert Zame, reports, rules and regulations of retirement fund, administrative committee minutes, 1944.
- Cloak Joint Board. Miscellaneous, 1940-1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Incl. Union request for reargument on impartial chairman's decision, April 1941; Procedure of the Board of Control.
- Congress, 1943-1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Corres. w. Congressmen on labor and non-labor legislation.
- D, 1943-1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Donnelly Garment Co. Case, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Dress Joint Board, N.Y. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Corres. w. Nathaniel M. Minkoff,
- Dress Joint Board. Health and Welfare Fund, 1944-1947 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Dress Joint Board. Minutes. Local managers meetings., 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Dress Joint Board. War Relief Fund Collections, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Erlich-Alter Committee, (n.d.). (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Elections, Local, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Elections, Local, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Incl. photographs.
- Elections, Local. [folder 1 of 2], 1939 (Box 3, Folder 11a)
  Samuel Perlmutter vs Isidore Nagler, campaign literature.
- Elections, Local. [folder 2 of 2], 1939 (Box 3, Folder 11b)
- Executive Board Cases, 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Cases, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Cases. [folder 1 of 2], 1944-1947 (Box 4, Folder 3a)
- Executive Board Cases. [folder 2 of 2], 1944-1947 (Box 4, Folder 3b)
- Executive Board Cases, Dress Joint Board, 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- F, 1943-1946 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Falikman, Moe, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Fiftieth Birthday celebration.
- Financial Statements, 1938-1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- G, 1943-1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Goldenberg, Max, 1943-1947 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- H, 1943-1947 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- I, 1943-1947 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Incl. Corres. w. Italian-American Labor Council Luigi Antonini president.
- Impartial Chairman Cloak Industry, 1943-1947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Corres. & decisions of George J. Mintzer, 1943; decisions of James J. Walker.
- Impartial Chairman Dress Industry, 1943-1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Decisions of Harry Uviller.
- Impartial Chairman. Isaac Slegmeister., 1943 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  George J. Mintzer decision, case Local 62 & Negligee, Lingerie, Allied Underwear, United Underwear Associations.
- Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Mfrs., Inc., 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Corres. on employment of cutters.
- Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Mfrs., Inc., 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- ILGWU. General Office, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Corres. w. David Dubinsky; Fredrick P. Umhey; releases.
- ILGWU. General Office, 1943-1945 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- ILGWU. Appeals Committee of the General Executive Board, 1943-1945 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Incl. decision on Arnold Ames case, 1945.
- ILGWU. Auditing Department, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Corres. w. Simeon Hamburger, audit report on Local, 1942- 43.
- ILGWU. Campaign Committee, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Literature, form letters, posters.
- ILGWU. Convention, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- ILGWU. Convention, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- ILGWU. Education Department, 1945-1947 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Corres. w. Mark Starr, articles.
- ILGWU. Education Department, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- ILGWU. Research Department, 1943-1947 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- ILGWU. War Relief Drive, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Invitations, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- J, 1943-1946 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Jewish Daily Forward, 1943-1947 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Judiciary Committee, 1943-1947 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- K, 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Kaplan, Irving, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Letter to firms on increases to cutters.
- L, 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Labor War Chest, AFL, N.Y., 1943-1946 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  League for Industrial Democracy, 1944-46.
- Liberal Party, 1944-1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Lieberman, Elias, 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Local Campaign Committee, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Local Health Fund, 1945-1947 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Locals, N.Y., 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Arranged numerically by local, 9-60.
- Locals, N.Y., 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Arranged numerically by local, 62-155.
- Locals, Out-Of-Town, 1945-1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Incl. Corres. w. Local 84, Los Angeles.
- Locals, Out-Of-Town, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- M, 1943-1947 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Requests and Inquiries (Box 8, Folder 4)
- N, 1943-1947 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Incl. Corres. w. Negro Labor Committee, 1943-47.
- National Coat and Suit Recovery Board, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Releases.
- National Coat and Suit Recovery Board, 1943-1947 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Investigations.
- National Committee for Labor Palestine, (Histadrut), 1944-1947 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- National Committee for Labor Palestine, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- New York State Labor Department, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Incl. N.Y.S. Bd. of Mediation letters.
- 0, 1944-1947 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Old Age Benefits, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training, 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- P, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Pioneer Women's Organization, 1943-1947 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Pioneer Youth of America, Inc., 1943-44.
- R, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  Incl. Corres. w. Rand School of Social Science, 1943-44.
- Reports, Local 10, 1942-1945 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- S, 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Schlesinger, Emil, 1944-1947 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Incl. Schlesinger letter on eliminating office of General Business Agent of Misc. Division. 1947.
- Social Democratic Federation New York City, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Starr, Mark. William B. Herlands report, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Commissioner, City of New York, Dept. of Investigation, to Fiorello LaGuardia on Mark Starr Case, April 1943.
- Stulberg, Louis. [folder 1 of 2], 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 4a)
  Incl. Corres. w. local members in armed services.
- Stulberg, Louis. [folder 2 of 2], 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 4b)
- T, 1943-1947 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Taft-Hartley Act, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Treasury Department, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Corres., Treasury Dept., releases on War Savings Bonds.
- U, 1943-1947 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Unemployment Registration, 1943-1945 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Incl. distribution of relief funds, 1943-45.
- Union Health Center, 1942-1947 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Incl. reports, 1942.47.
- United Hebrew Trades, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- United Jewish Appeal, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- United States Dept. of Labor-Bureau of Labor Statistics; Bulletins, 1943-1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Unity House, 1943-1947 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- V, 1943-1947 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Veterans Job Training Program, 1946-1947 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- W, 1943-1947 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Incl. rulings by Wage Stabilization Board. 1946.
- War Labor Board, 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Cases on wage adjustments & bonus adjustments for firms.
- War Labor Board, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  Cases.
- War Labor Board, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- War Relief Agencies, 1943-1946 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Incl. Red Cross, Russian War Relief, Inc.
- Welfare Dept., N.Y., 1943-1947 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Workmen's Circle, Branch 310, 1940-1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- World War II. [folder 1 of 2], 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 7a)
  Corres. w. members in armed services.
- World War II. [folder 1 of 2], 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 7b)
- X-Y-Z, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 8)